

# TALBOT FRENCH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with experience in creating well functioning programs, identifying errors, and a keen eye for creating visually pleasing front ends. Adaptive ability to custom design through multiple digital media programs (Photoshop, Illustrator) and well as vast communication skills to allow for cooperation on any team.

# **SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- SQL / MS SQL
- C# / MVC / Entity Framework
- Visual Studio
- Azure
- Photoshop

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

Talbot French
1565 N University Ave
Provo, Utah
84606(817)995-0941
Talbot.french@gmail.com
LinkedIn
Github
Portfolio

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Team player
- Fluent in Spanish
- Analytical thinker
- Creative
- Self Motivated

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### Prosper IT | 2019 - Present

- Team development project creating an MVC 5 through Azure in Visual Studio. Multiple web pages using C#, .NET, MVC, MS SQL. Developed PartialViews relating to buttons to ensure consistency on front-end as well as efficiency on the backend. Stylized and edited Navbar allowing for easy access to alternative webpages.

#### MISSION LEADER

#### Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints | 2017 - 2019

- Lead teams of missionaries in their proselytizing efforts including establishing meetings and conducting training of ways to implement new techniques. Organized and directed community service projects in multiple provinces and worked with communities to establish and execute youth outreach programs.

#### **EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT**

#### HRH French Bulldogs | 2012 - 2017

- Marketing and advertising assistant worked hand in hand with lead web developer and attended sales meeting as company representative.

### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### THE TECH ACADEMY

#### **Software Development**

- I was trained in the use of multiple coding languages, and taught in depth to utilize them to create a variety of programs. My education included a foundation of technological terms and formal introduction into the industry with an internship where I helped develop a web MVC along with a team of other developers.

#### **NORTHWEST HIGH SCHOOL**

#### **Graduated on Distinguished track**

- TSA State award, Metal sculptures on 5 pounds
- Captain, Ultimate Frisbee
- Member, Varsity Football
- Member, Varsity Track